在一个可视化布局的编辑器上设计布局很简单
Building something that looks great in the visual layout editor is the easy
你同样需要考虑不同尺寸的屏幕以及屏幕的方向
part. You also need to consider different screens and orientations. As you
当你开始设计你程序的UI时 很可能会想去用你开发时候用的设备参数
begin to layout your UI, there's a temptation to build it pixel perfect for
去试图构建适合这个参数的像素完美的布局
the device you happen to be using at the time. This is reinforced by
而你的编程时用的设备屏幕大小通常不会改变
the fact that your apps window doesn't generally change size while it's running.
所以你无法随意调整屏幕的大小
So you can't just grab the lower i-corner and grow and
来看看它在不同设备上有什么不同表现 但是如果你开发过网络或者桌面应用
shrink your app to see how it behaves. But if you've ever developed for
你就会知道这有什么缺点
the web or desktop, you know this static approach is a bad idea.
Android首次发布时 屏幕标准是480*320的HVGA
When Android first launched, HVGA 480 by 320 resolution screens were standard.
那时候我们可以用绝对布局定义每个元素的位置
As we began exploring how to build engaging user experiences on those devices,
来开发高用户体验的应用程序
we could use absolute layouts to define the exact location of each
但是一年以内 第一个WVGA屏幕的Android手机发布了
screen element. But within a year, the first WVGA Android phones were released.
而现在Android运行在各种尺寸屏幕的平板手机、平板、TV
And now Android runs on everything from phones to phablets, tablets, TVs and
还有穿戴式设备
wearables with any screen size, resolution and aspect ratio you can imagine.
桌面开发和Web开发上 你可以用panels或CSS
So, just like desktop or web where you might use panels or
你的Android UI需要适应各种屏幕
CSS, your Android UI needs to scale based on the screen it's running within,
这就是不使用绝对布局的原因
which is why absolute layout was deprecated.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
利用LinearLayout布局、RelativeLayout布局、
In favor of layouts like LinearLayout, RelativeLayout and
GridLayout布局 来构建动态大小的布局
GridLayout, they can dynamically resize and
以适应越来越多样化的Android设备 请遵照响应式布局的准则来设计
adapt to any screen, following the principles of responsive design.